Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/chiphuyen (LinkedIn) huyenchip.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence
Programming
Machine Learning

Languages

Vietnamese (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional) Spanish (Professional Working)

Honors-Awards

Author of the best-selling book of the year 2012 on Tiki.vn

Author of the 3rd and 9th best-selling book of the year 2013 on Tiki.vn

FAHASA's Top 10 Reader's Choice Books in 2014

Winner of Techcombank's Essay Contest

Ericsson Innovation Awards ' Regional Winner

Chip Huyen

ML Engineer @ Snorkel Al | Adjunct lecturer @ Stanford | LinkedIn Top Voices 2019

Mountain View

Summary

I'm Chip Huyen, a writer and computer scientist. I'm currently with Snorkel AI, a data-first end-to-end platform for developing AI applications. I'll be teaching Machine Learning Systems Design at Stanford from January 2021.

Previously, I was with NVIDIA, Netflix, Primer, Baomoi.com (acquired by VNG). I helped launch Coc Coc - Vietnam's second most popular web browser with 20+ million monthly active users.

In my free time, I travel and write. After high school, I went to Brunei for a 3-day vacation which turned into a 3-year trip through Asia, Africa, and South America. During my trip, I worked as a Bollywood extra, a casino hostess, and a street performer.

I'm the author of four bestselling Vietnamese books. I'm working on an English book on machine learning interviews.

Experience

Snorkel Al

ML Engineer & Open Source Lead December 2019 - Present (1 year)

Snorkel Flow is an end-to-end platform that focuses on a revolutionary new programmatic approach to labeling, building, and managing training datasets, enabling a new level of rapid, iterative development and deployment of Al applications.

NVIDIA

1 year 6 months

Senior Deep Learning Engineer October 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 3 months) California Bringing the latest AI research into production. First new hire on AI Apps team.

Deep Learning Engineer Intern July 2018 - September 2018 (3 months)

Contributed to OpenSeq2Seq.

Stanford University

3 years 1 month

Instructor

January 2017 - March 2018 (1 year 3 months)

United States

I proposed, wrote the syllabus for, and taught the course CS 20SI:

"TensorFlow for Deep Learning Research".

Section Leader

March 2015 - June 2017 (2 years 4 months)

United States

Teaching weekly 50-minute sections, grading programming assignments, and holding weekly helper hours.

Content taught included but not limited to:

CS106A: basic Java syntax and data structures, Object-Oriented software architectures,

Interactors and Graphic User Interfaces.

CS106B: basic C++ syntax and data structures, recursion, complexity evaluation, pointer arithmetic, implementation of data structures such as trees and priority queues, graph search algorithms.

Research Assistant, Artificial Intelligence Lab January 2016 - May 2016 (5 months)

Working on a project that aims to create a control system that allows a robot to perform automatic programmed operations for mundane tasks in a confined space, such as the wing of a Boeing aircraft.

My part is to implement SLAM (Simultaneous localization and mapping): a program that detects and maps static objects in the surrounding environment so that the robot can keep track of its location within it.

Research Assistant, Astronautics Department June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months) Implementing object detection schemes using minimal computational resources to assist on-board satellite pose estimation.

Input: 2D images of a non-communicating object in space.

Output: velocity and direction in which the object is traveling.

Method: detect landmark and spatial features then match these features with

those of a 3D model of an aircraft.

Netflix

Research Assistant
June 2017 - September 2017 (4 months)

Los Gatos

I work on a research project to explore different approaches for machine translation.

Primer.ai
Machine Learning Intern
July 2016 - September 2016 (3 months)
San Francisco

Primer is an NLP startup with a team of less than 10 people. Its clients consist of Fortune 50 companies and government agencies. My job is to implement papers to evaluate if the technologies can be used for the company's products.

The University of Edinburgh Research Assistant, School of Informatics June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months)

I work with Professor Adam Lopez's research group. Our goal is to build machine learning systems that can predict the meaning of an input sentence, or predict a sentence from the meaning representation. The data that we work with is Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR).

Cốc Cốc

Creative Director July 2012 - March 2013 (9 months)

Led market research & product management for Cốc Cốc browser, Vietnam's 2nd most popular browser with 20M monthly active users. Cốc Cốc is the biggest Vietnamese digital advertising publisher. During my time there, it had 400+ employees.

Free Hugs Vietnam (FHV)
Founder
June 2009 - June 2012 (3 years 1 month)
Page 3 of 4

FHV is a non-profit organization that:

- provides volunteering opportunities with international organizations for Vietnamese students to help them improve English.
- organizes workshops, competitions, and speaker series for Vietnamese students.
- provides assistance to NGOs and international volunteer groups when they come to Vietnam.

InvestVietnam Editor & Community Manager 2009 - 2010 (1 year)

Managed the online community for Vietnam's largest start-up community with

Education

80,000 members.

Vietnam

Stanford University
Master's Degree, Computer Science

Stanford University
Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science